翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
As we work our way through this method,
当我们通过这种方法工作时
I'm going to go back one slide so that we can consult this.
我要往后退一张幻灯片，以便我们可以参考
So let's jump in.
开始吧
So we need to change removeLast-- or, sorry-- addLast
我们需要更改 removeLast ...对不起，addLast
so that it can handle the array getting too big.
以使它可以处理过大的数组
So we'll have a little special case here, and we'll say, if--
这里有一个小的特例
OK, what was it-- size equals items.length.
size == items.length
OK, it's good to have that very concretely in our mind.
牢记这一点
Then we need do a few things.
然后需要做几件事
First, we need to create a new array, which I'll call A.
首先创建一个新数组，我将其命名为 a
And it's going to be a new int array, which is going to be of size size plus 1.
它是一个新的整型数组，大小为 size+1
Then what we're going to do is copy everything over.
然后把所有东西都复制过来
You could also use a loop if you wanted.
如果需要还可以使用循环
But I'm going to copy everything over using System.arraycopy.
但我使用 System.arraycopy 复制所有内容
What should we do?
该怎么办？
Well, we need a copy from the old items array starting at position 0 to the new array, A, starting at position 0.
我们需要从旧 items 的位置0开始复制到新数组 a 的位置0
And then finally, we need to say how many items.
最后指明复制多少项
And it's going to be size items.
应该有 size 项
So there are a hundred things we need to copy.
也就是复制100项
And you'll notice that IntelliJ here has helpfully told us what the source and destination positions are.
你会注意到 IntelliJ 已经告诉我们源位置和目标位置是什么
And that could be, in theory, handy, though the coloring I have set up is pretty impossible to read.
从理论上讲，这可能很方便，尽管我设置的颜色几乎无法阅读
Next up-- now, we've now copied the items over.
我们已经复制了这些项
So at this point, we now need to change items to be equal to A.
所以此时我们现在需要将 items 更改为等于 a
And then size plus equals 1-- all of this stuff happens down here.
然后 size += 1，所有事情都发生在下面
So this will handle putting the new item in the last position.
这将新的项放到最后一位
And this will increase the size.
这会增加 size
So these last two steps-- or sorry.
最后这两步...抱歉
These two steps here were already part of our code.
这两个步骤已经是我们代码的一部分
So at this point, we now have an addLast method that should work properly.
此时我们有了一个应该可以正常工作的 addLast 方法
Now, in the real world, if I was doing any real programming at all, I would run some kind of tests.
现实中，如果我在真实地编程的话，我会运行一些测试代码
In fact, I have this entire test file.
事实上我有完整的测试文件
But because we haven't really talked about it--
但是我们还没真正讨论过它
we will next lecture--
下一堂课再说
I'm not going to run it now.
暂时不运行
But what I want to warn you is that the way I've been programming in this lecture is,  in some ways, a bad example
但我想提醒你的是，我在这堂课中的编程方式，在某些方面是一个反面教材
because I've been writing giant blobs of code without doing any testing.
因为我在没有做任何测试的情况下编写了大量的代码
And if you do the same thing on project 1a,
如果你在项目1a 这样做
you'll probably have a sad time.
可能会有段悲伤的时光
So I'll give you some tips in the next lecture about better incremental development.
下一节课中我会给你一些更好的增量开发的提示
But for the purposes of this lecture,
但对于这堂课
for this narrative, for something that I've practiced time and time again,
对于这个我已经练习了一次又一次的东西
chances are I probably haven't messed up anything too severely.
应该不会把事情搞得太糟
But if I do, then I guess I'll get to re-record one of these videos.
但如果失败了，我想我会重新录制
So this right here is a perfectly wonderful addLast method.
这是一个非常棒的 addLast 方法
But I'm going to make one change to this to make my code a little nicer and more organized.
但我将对此做一个更改，使我的代码更好、更有条理
So specifically, I'm going to note that this whole process here--
具体地说，我要指出这里的整个过程...
this resizing process-- could actually be made into its own method.
这个 resizing 过程，实际上可以变成它自己的方法
So I'm going to do that because I just think it is nicer.
我这么做是觉得这样更好
So I'm going to say, resizes the underlying array to the target capacity.
将底层数组的大小调整为目标容量
That's what it's going to look like.
这就是它的样子
And that's going to be a private void method called Resize.
这将是一个名为 resize 的私有方法
It takes a capacity argument.
需要 capacity 参数
And this code is all going to do the resizing.
这段代码将调整大小
Now, instead of being size plus one,
不再是 size+1
this version is going to resize to some arbitrary capacity--
它将会调整到某个任意的容量
just a little nicer.
稍微好点
So I now made a resize method.
我现在完成了一个 resize 方法
And so here, when I want to act-- when I run out of room-- oops.
当我想行动时...当我用完空间时...
I messed up slightly.
我搞砸了
This if statement should not be inside resize.
if 语句不应位于 resize 内部
We're going to move it into addLast.
把它移到 addLast 中
So if the size is equal to items.length,
if (size == items.length)
then we will say resize to size plus.
执行 resize(size + 1)
That's just the way I've chosen organize my code.
这是我选择组织代码的方式
You may disagree.
你可能不同意
So at this point, we've now written an addLast method.
我们已经编写了一个 addLast 方法
We have a resize method that keeps things going.
有一个 resize 方法
Let's fix our indentation.
修改一下缩进
We could use the IntelliJ shortcut, but I did it manually.
可以使用 IntelliJ 的快捷方式，但我是手动的
And there we go.
好了
We now have code that adds to the array.
现在我们有了添加到数组中的代码
And now, the array is infinitely extensible.
数组现在是可无限扩展的
It actually does the thing it's supposed to do.
它实际上做了应该做的事情
So let's debrief this code a little bit.
稍微汇报一下代码
So our addLast method, we said, if size is equal to items.length, do all this stuff,
我们的 addLast 方法，如果 size == items.length，做这些事
though we showed that an alternate approach is to say,
我们展示了另一种方法是
if the size is equal to items.length, then use a special resize function.
如果 size == items.length，则使用特殊的 resize 函数
Now why would this be better?
为什么这样更好呢？
This is something that you could actually test separately.
这个东西实际上可以单独测试
You could write tests.
你可以写测试
You could use the visualizer to actually look and see what it's doing.
可以使用可视化工具来查看它做了什么
And by breaking your code into little tiny pieces,
通过将你的代码分解成很小的片段
it just makes it much easier to maintain, to understand.
只会让它更容易维护和理解
This is easier to read as another programmer who wants to maintain the AList class.
这对另一个想要维护 AList 的程序员来说更易读
So I think this approach is better,
所以我觉得这个方法更好
but you might have done something like this.
但你可能做过这样的事
After you've done project 1a, we're actually going to have a little thing in lab where I'll let you discuss implementations with each other.
做完项目1a 后，我们实际上在 lab 里有个小东西，我会让你们互相讨论实现
And hopefully you can find other little tricks like that you might have missed or others might have come up with.
希望你能找到漏掉的、或者其他人想出来的其他小技巧
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）